<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Life...Part B]]></title>
  <link href="http://tracyb.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tracyb.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-08T23:32:55-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://tracyb.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tracy Baumann]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[And the rollercoaster continues...]]></title>
    <link href="http://tracyb.github.io/blog/2013/10/08/and-the-rollercoaster-continues-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-08T22:29:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://tracyb.github.io/blog/2013/10/08/and-the-rollercoaster-continues-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Saturday was Installfest &ndash; I left the DaVinci Institute feeling exhilarated and excited about all of the &ldquo;stuff&rdquo; I added to my shiny new MacBook:</p>

<p>Homebrew &ndash; software that references beer? I&rsquo;m in!</p>

<p>iTerm2 &ndash; feeling like a psuedo techie now</p>

<p>Google Chrome &ndash; adios Safari</p>

<p>AirParrot &ndash; hey, learning stuff I can use at home too!</p>

<p>Anki &ndash; who doesn&rsquo;t love flashcards?</p>

<p>Evernote &ndash; this is definitely going to come in handy</p>

<p>Skitch &ndash; screen shots = money for a beginning student</p>

<p>Flycut &ndash; not proficient enough to dabble in this&hellip;yet</p>

<p>Moom &ndash; my favorite new app, can&rsquo;t wait to learn the keyboard shortcuts</p>

<p>HipChat &ndash; misery loves company :)</p>

<p>Github &ndash; the sticker is so cool, this must be great</p>

<p>On Sunday I tackled the first few homework problems. These were &ndash; dare I say &ndash; easy? The exercises introduced concepts such as objects, variables, assignment. I was feeling confident and&hellip;smart?</p>

<p>At 10 o&#8217;clock on Monday night, I left the first class with heavy eyes and a heavy heart. Managed to keep up with the class (kinda-sorta) but wow, there is a lot to learn. We used Octopress to start our own blogs. I&rsquo;ve always wanted to start a blog so I was eager to jump in.</p>

<p>Tonight I set out to finish what we started with the blog. After poking around for about 2 hours, I finally remembered how to do everything we did the night before using the terminal and RubyMine. Was I actually sleeping with my eyes open in class? :)</p>

<p>First, I changed the look of my blog using a free theme from octothemes.com. Chose an acceptable (not perfect) theme and linked it to my Github repo. From there I followed the steps to install as a Git submodule. Next I applied the theme to my blog with the following commands:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>rake install[theme name]
</span><span class='line'>rake generate</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>followed by Control-C and</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>rake preview</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Then I finally figured out how to add a new post:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>rake new_post["Title"]
</span><span class='line'>rake generate</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Followed by a search in RubyMine using Shift-Command-N to search for the post I just created. Started writing&hellip;</p>

<p>I hopped over to google chrome and peeked at the outcome at <a href="http://localhost:4000.">http://localhost:4000.</a></p>

<p>Hmmnn&hellip;my test post from class was cramping my style, but how to delete?</p>

<p>A quick google search and I learned how to navigate to the source file and delete the post.</p>

<p>Ta da! My very first blog!</p>

<p>Conclusion: the teacher sure made this look easy! Feeling pretty good for a newbie.</p>

<p>Until class tomorrow night&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
